Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
"Great Detective Conan"
"Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi"
If I recall, this case was...
This date...
Do you remember something?
No...
July 9th...
That was Eri-san's case.
Mom was a murder suspect.
Ah! That disgusting day!
"Tokyo District Court, Komehana Branch"
"July 9th, 2010"
That color's a little too flashy.
"Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend - Mori Ran"
Really?
Unless it's a deep red, I can't get into
that fighting spirit, now can I?
"Lawyer, Ran's Mother
Kisaki Eri"
Today's for revenge.
Revenge?
Revenge on who?
Ran...
Whatever happens today,
don't be frightened.
Eh?
"High School Student Detective
Kudo Shin'ichi"
Flowers maybe?
She'd like underwear.
Deep red ones.
Eri-san.
In foreign countries, it's normal to give
your lover underwear as a present.
This is a present for Ran, isn't it?
I'll go with you.
Well, she's not my lover
and this isn't a foreign country.
Then anything's fine.
It's a man's habit to be unclear.
Ah, that's right.
This is just an ordinary thank-you gift.
Wouldn't food be fine?
That'd be the worst.
You don't express any
passion at all with that.
Do that and you'll lose the woman.
Eri-san what was it?
The first present your husband gave you?
This.
Ehh... His choice was
comparatively good for him, wasn't it?
What "choice" did he make?
I'm the one who chose and bought it.
Should have guessed, huh?
Sorry! Ah! Thanks for waiting.
Yo.
"Courtroom"
"Tokyo District Court,
Komehana Branch, Courtroom 305"
Dad?
Ala? Sir. What are you doing here?
"Private Detective
Mori Kogoro"
She called for me...
Since it's for my precious Reika-chan's trial,
I just had to come.
What on earth are you intending by coming?
Hmm...
Your precious Reika-chan, huh...
Hmmf.
You aren't Reiko-chan's
lawyer today, are you?
If you call out that name this time...
...I'll kill you.
Reika-chan!
"Defendant
Saito Reika"
You can do it!
"The defendant in this trial is a hostess
at the snack bar 'Mint Rose,' Saito Reika."
"On May 28th while on her day shift..."
"...she was arrested as a suspect in the theft
of 10 million yen from the safe at her work."
($125,000)
"However..."
"She denies the charges..."
"Lawyer
Uchida Shin'ya"
"...and claims she has an alibi
for the time the theft occurred."
"Eri-san is an important
witness proving her alibi..."
"...she says."
"Public Prosecutor
Kamikawa Takumi"
"This Kamikawa is the Tokyo District
Public Prosecutor's Office Ace Prosecutor."
"Undefeated Ace
Hanagata Public Prosecutor, Kamikawa Takumi"
He's an incredible Prosecutor.
Ah... Mama!'
"Snack Bar Mint Rose's
Itano Masako"
That woman's a lying cat burglar.
You feel like being a supporter
of a woman like that?
Mama.
There's no reason Reika-chan
could be the criminal!
Since I, the great detective whose name reverberates
around the world, Kogoro Mori, have come...
...I will immediately solve
any kind of mystery!
Who's that?
Court is in session.
"2010, Case 1687
Snack Bar "Mint Rose"
Theft (Stolen Cash) Case
3rd Trial"
"The defendant Reika..."
"Witness for the Defense
Kisaki Eri"
"...claims as her alibi that at the time of the crime
she witnessed Eri-san at some other place."
"Therefore..."
"...the essential focus point in proving
the propriety of Reika's crime..."
"...was whether Eri-san actually
was there at that place."
When the snack bar, Mint Rose, was robbed of
10 million yen on May 28th at around midnight...
...where were you, Kisaki Eri-san?
Objection!
That doesn't prove the defendant's alibi.
If the defendant and Kisaki-san
were at the same place...
...the defendant couldn't have
committed that crime. Isn't that right?
Will you withdraw your objection?
Kisaki-san.
Where were you?
In Haidocho...
...at a love hotel.
I saw you.
You were with some oily old man.
Mom was...
She was at a love hotel with a man?
Reika-san must have seen them
around the area.
Eri...
Is it true you were at a love hotel?
Tha... that's an affair!
A legitimate betrayal!
Quiet!
Ehh... It's been testified that
the defendant Saito...
...on the same day and time, witnessed you
and a man entering the love hotel, "Peach-Peach."
Damn!
A place I don't know about.
Here's the evidence.
I will submit to the Presiding Judge security camera
footage from the entrance of the hotel "Peach-Peach..."
...as evidence.
I see.
That video will be proof the testimonies
of Eri-san and Reika-san match.
I was really surprised.
That some dirty old man and the
beauty lawyer would be going into a love hotel.
What kind of man was it?
Didn't I just tell you?
A dirty. Old. Man.
No matter how pretty she may be, a middle-aged
woman just doesn't get her pick of men.
How pitiful.
I was already in the area.
Reika-san, please stop.
Because you're the defendant, you must stay calm.
Inexcusable!
Completely inexcusable!
If it were me,
I couldn't stand such a dirty man.
Being held by such a guy...
Ah, it makes me shudder.
You...
Even though you have
a fine and handsome husband...
...to go off with another man...
Did you think I would forgive you for that?!
Think of Ran's feelings!
All of you think so, don't you?
That I'm so much younger
and prettier than that old woman there.
Say, Lawyer Uchida.
I went out of my way to testify
for this person's sake.
What's this about?
I'm sorry.
But it's the truth.
You have a glib
and slippery tongue, don't you?
It's just the truth.
Stop it now.
If you talk any further than this...
...your own words will take your life.
Hmm...
What you mean is, you'll kill me.
Yes.
Then, as you wish.
Bang!
Reika-chan! Reika-chan.
Someone!
Someone hurry and call for an ambulance!
It's already too late.
She's been shot in the head and killed.
Ala.
Is she really dead?
How regrettable.
Eri!
Why would you do such a thing...
It couldn't be helped that she died.
What was that!?
A person is dead!
Ala?
You've defied me, too.
In that case, just like her,
I'll kill you with my finger gun.
Oi. Don't tell me you...
Who will be next?
You?
Or maybe...
...you.
That's an interesting trick, Lawyer Kisaki.
If a person really
can be killed by finger gun...
Then by all means,
please shoot me with your gun.
Ala, are you sure?
Shin'ichi, stop it!
Mom, please stop joking around, too.
Eri!
I misjudged you.
An adulterer who kills.
Were you that lonely without me?
Huh?
What stupidity are you talking about?
Please stop this already.
More importantly than me...
The present we talked about earlier.
What have you picked out in your head?
The expectations hidden in a present
are etched into this fingertip.
If you choose something poorly...
...I'll kill you.
Sir, I'll leave this old lady to you.
You should kill your wife.
What are you saying?
Eri!
However alluring I may be,
you shouldn't have killed her! Not her!
You there! Calm down!
But this woman killed Reika-chan!
And it is the unworthy I...
...the great detective Mori Kogoro,
who is at fault...
Due to me, two women fought over me
and one of those women died.
I...
I can't forgive my allure!
Sergeant!
Take that person there away.
Ah... Wai... wait a minute.
Presiding judge! Presiding judge!
Dad!
I'm disappointed, Lawyer Kisaki.
I can't stand that attitude of yours.
Presiding judge. Please have
Lawyer Kisaki arrested right away.
She is the prime suspect in
the murder of Saito Reika-san.
Shin'ichi?
Very well.
Thank you very much.
"MPD Investigation Unit One
Sato Miwako"
Detective Sato.
Kudo-kun.
The corpse...?
One shot, bang, to the head.
An instant death.
Sato-san.
Takagi-kun, how'd it go?
Wherever I look, I can't find the weapon.
"MPD Investigation Unit One
Takagi Wataru"
It clearly looks like a bullet wound...
...but it's impossible to have
brought a gun into the courtroom.
Since just the one shot was fired...
...it's possible a metal tube with a detonator could
function to have a bullet shot out of it, right?
So we should first locate
who used the weapon.
Prosecutor Kamikawa,
what did you notice at the crime scene...
The bizarre behavior of Lawyer Kisaki.
She herself said she had killed her
and gave what could be called a confession.
The one who killed Saito Reika-san was you,
Lawyer Kisaki, wasn't it?
No.
You're wrong.
Are you retracting your earlier statements?
Common sense alone
should tell you, shouldn't it?
Don't tell me you actually believe a person
can be killed with a finger gun, do you?
Then, all that earlier was a joke, huh?
Obviously.
Or do you intend to
write up in your report...
"Deadly weapon,
a human's second finger (index finger)"
..."Deadly weapon,
a human's second finger (index finger)"?
What a laugh.
Say, Shin'ichi.
Mom is...
Mom isn't the criminal, right?
Shin'ichi?
That woman could have done it.
Eh?
Reika and your mother had
a huge fight over Kogoro-chan.
It was pandemonium.
Pandemonium.
Ow, ow, ow!
"Reika!"
If this story about Lawyer Kisaki
and Reika-san is true...
...then she would have a motive.
They were fighting over a man.
They clashed at a hotel, didn't they?
Reika and that lawyer.
No matter how you look at it, it's strange.
Say, Shin'ichi...
Mom was talking about it.
That she was going...
...to take revenge today.
Ran, that was...
But, there's no way
Mom could be the criminal.
It's impossible that Mom
could be the criminal.
Prosecutor Kamikawa...
...about that security camera video from the
love hotel that was at issue during the trial.
Is there anything shown on that?
On the video?
It's possible something will come from it.
Something that the Lawyer Kisaki...
...is trying to hide.
At the same time Reika-san
was outside of this love hotel...
...she saw Kisaki-san with a man, right?
Yeah. That's why Reika-san
doesn't show up in the video.
Lawyer Uchida, how did you come
into possession of this video?
After hearing her testimony,
I hurriedly looked for it.
It was a big help that the video
was still around.
Speaking of which...
...before she was killed, those reckless remarks
Reika-san spat out and her attitude...
Were those under your directions,
Lawyer Uchida?
Nothing of the sort!
All it would do is make a bad impression
on the judge, wouldn't it?
I can't even begin to guess
what it was that got her so upset.
It seems you were at the love hotel at the
time of the crime, just as Saito Reika testified.
I didn't testify I wasn't, did I?
With this, Reika-san's alibi
has been proven.
We can say she was innocent.
Eri-san...
Who is this man that you're with?
You won't answer?
"Eri-san squatted."
"Finger gun."
"Love hotel."
"Revenge."
"Today's for revenge."
"A quarrel with grabbing."
"Reckless remarks."
The pieces have been gathered.
All that's left...
...is to prove the truth.
Eri-san.
You didn't want that video
earlier to be seen, did you?
That's why you killed Reika-san.
Shin'ichi?
Hey, what are you saying?
Ran.
By my deduction...
...Eri-san is the criminal.
The Lawyer Kisaki had to kill
Saito Reika-san in this courtroom.
Her reason...
...was that this video would then
no longer be disclosed to the court.
What was on this video...
...was certain evidence of your adultery.
By allowing this to run...
...your divorce would
have been made definite.
You say that so dryly.
I could divorce
such a man as him at any time.
Still Lawyer Kisaki...
...you were quarreling
with Reika-san over Kogoro.
That was surely a woman's jealousy.
It was just pride.
Shape up, Shin'ichi!
Ran...
Mom couldn't kill a person.
Shin'ichi, you know that, don't you!
Because Mom is honest...
...and always right and a perfect mother.
Ran.
What is this?
Does the perfect person...
...go to a love hotel with a suspicious man?
Eh? That's...
Ran-san.
Hasn't it been a burden for Lawyer Kisaki?
It's the height of her evaluation period.
Lies...
I won't believe it.
I absolutely won't believe it.
My daughter's right.
I am not the criminal.
The point is, making a fuss over
a video is a weak foundation.
It's well-founded.
"Reika-chan! Reika-chan!"
When you fell down...
...it was to pick up the mortal weapon
you had dropped, wasn't it?
And then, you picked a quarrel with
everyone so you could cheat your movements.
Where's your evidence?
You must have evidence, don't you?
After the incident, you were
immediately placed under guard.
Therefore...
...you should still be
concealing the weapon.
Do a body search.
Excuse me.
I couldn't find a deadly weapon.
Eh? Why?
Is Lawyer Kisaki the criminal... or not?
Well...
It's impossible the excellent Lawyer Kisaki not
to have someplace she could hide it quickly.
In that case...
...the deadly weapon could only be there.
Please untie your hair, Lawyer Kisaki.
What is it? Can't you do it?
The deadly weapon.
I've found the deadly weapon.
There's no doubt that she's the criminal.
Is that really the mortal weapon?
Here, take a good look.
In here's the equipment to fire a bullet.
Seems to be an ordinary tube of lipstick.
At last you've revealed you're at fault,
haven't you, Prosecutor Kamikawa.
It was shown in the
criminal investigation report...
...that the mortal weapon was
a metal tube of some sort.
Not knowing either its features
nor its dimensions...
...there wasn't anyone but the criminal who would
conclude the deadly weapon was this lipstick.
And...
The real mortal weapon is in this.
Prosecutor Kamikawa, don't you think
it's been shown at last with this?
What's that?
The riddle of the lie from
the weapon's victim.
In other words...
...what remains in this court is just
the guy with the one and only truth.
You made a gun from the same
tube of lipstick that Eri-san had...
...and then smuggled it into the court.
And then you waited for a chance
when Reika-san was making a fuss...
...to aim and fire the gun...
You then rolled the gun to
the witness stand where Eri-san was.
When it rolled up to me,
I thought it was my lipstick.
But when I picked it up, I noticed it was
strangely hot and so then I understood.
That if my fingerprints were left on it...
...I would be tagged as the criminal.
So I indeed acted suspiciously
and gave a signal to Shin'ichi-kun.
I deduced that this line was,
"Use your head."
"What present have you
picked out in your head?"
The "present" was lipstick.
"Fingertip" meant fingerprint.
By "If you choose something poorly,"
she meant deadly weapon.
"If you choose something poorly..."
From those hints,
I understood Eri-san's message.
That when the deadly weapon wasn't found,
the criminal would surely give themselves away.
So at the moment
that man was making a fuss...
...I turned the mortal weapon
over to Shin'ichi-kun...
And I hid the weapon in this video case
for safe keeping.
Geez...
The two of you had me worried.
Kudo-kun.
You're under the impression the thing you saw
was the mortal weapon and that I dropped it.
Is there any evidence of that?
Then, how do you explain the mystery
of the lie Reika-san told?
Lie?
Before she was killed,
Reika-san told one big, fat lie.
The case of her alibi.
Reika-san wasn't in front of the
love hotel at the time of the crime.
She was stealing the money
from the snack bar.
How can you say such a thing?!
Because...
Right, Eri-san?
Right?
She was saying
some strange things, wasn't she?
Strange things?
Yes.
That I was together with
a little, dirty old man.
I don't get it.
What is this lie the victim was talking about?
Can't be helped.
Geez, then shouldn't you just
call for that little, dirty old man?
If you would please!
Tah-dah!
Thanks for waiting, Ladies and Gentlemen!
I am the famous
and great detective, Mori Kogoro!
We weren't particularly waiting...
And that "fame" doesn't seem
to be selling all that much.
What's that?
Saying I'm not popular!
That's just foolishness!
Well then...
...shall we look at the false evidence?
Ala?
Isn't that Kogoro-chan?
Dad?!
The man you went to a love hotel with...
was Dad?!
Ah! I remember!
That was the time Reika-san dumped me,
so I got drunk and called Eri.
Dad! You're the worst!
The man Eri-san was with
was Mori Kogoro.
Strange, isn't it?
Kogoro was a regular customer at her bar.
If she really had witnessed us,
she should have just said so.
"I saw Kisaki and Mori
going into a love hotel."
In other words...
...you could say that Reika-san really
didn't see Eri-san or Kogoro-san.
Then how could Reika-san,
who wasn't at this place, know about it?
Reika-san actually didn't see Eri-san.
She learned about this video
from someone else.
Prosecutor Kamikawa.
You were in charge of...
...that tax evasion case against the love hotel
"Peach-Peach Group" until recently, weren't you?
"In Charge of the Peach-Peach Group's
Tax Evasion Case"
The only one who could have given her the
information that was on this video in advance...
...was you, Prosecutor Kamikawa.
Was the motive tangled up in love and money?
Weren't you receiving
unlawful money from Reika-san?
The Elite Public Prosecutor.
She...
She was completely evil!
She was totally mad about me.
I was doing well what with a lover,
money coming in, and a promotion at work.
My life was just a lump of good fortune.
Then...
"Don't mess around with me!"
As soon as she was arrested,
she had her hand out in return.
Unless I got her out of prison immediately
for stealing that 10 million yen for my sake...
...she said she would reveal everything
that had happened between us before.
The biggest blunder of my life was in
getting caught up with that ill-natured woman.
For the sake of a special man like me...
...she should be expected to die!
What's so special about you?!
You're no different than
any other criminal anywhere.
You're just a tiny, stupid man.
Prosecutor Kamikawa! No...
Kamikawa Takumi.
You are under arrest for suspicion
in the murder of Saito Reika.
Ran, I'm sorry.
You must have been frightened.
Yeah.
But, it's okay.
I trusted in Mom, after all.
Say, your father...
When we went into that hotel, he passed out
and went to sleep right away.
Huh? Ah... Dad's the worst!
Choose your man carefully, okay?
Don't run away, Sir.
Oi, boy detective.
Choose your wife carefully, okay?
Farewell!
In that case, the only thing that's clear
is that Dad's the worst, isn't it?
Wha... what are you doing?
It was only because of my play-acting
that we were able to settle that case.
If so, then it's the deadly weapon...
"Lipstick"
Oi! What case is it this time?
Whaa! Beautiful!
What's this?
If I recall, this dress is...
My dress!
You aren't a wife yet!
It's not Ran's.
This is the bride whose wedding
didn't work out because of Ran's father.
Eh?
Eh? Me?
"Murder At A Wedding!"
"Obsession of Women Over the Groom"
"This Drama is Fictional"